这是二零一七年普通高等学校招生
全国统一考试英语科听力部分。
该部分分为第一、第二两节。
注意。
回答听力部分时，请先将答案
标在试卷上。
听力部分结束前，你将有两分钟的时间
将你的答案转涂到答题卡上。
现在是听力试音时间。
语音到此结束。
听力考试正式开始。
请看听力部分第。
一节。
第一节，听下面五段对话，
每段对话后有一个小题。
从题中所给的
三个选项中选出。
最佳选项。
听完每段对话后，你都有十秒钟的时间
来回答有关小题和阅读下一小题。
每段对话仅读一遍。
例如，现在你有五秒钟的时间
看试卷上的例题。
你将听到以下内容：“
Yes, it's 9.15.
你将有五秒钟的时间，将正确答案
标在试卷上。
衬衫的价格为。
为九磅十五便是，所以
你选择
项，并将其标在试卷上。
现在，你有五秒钟的时间
阅读第一小题的有关内容。
Let's go for a nice walk into the country this afternoon.
I certainly could enjoy the exercise, but I've agreed to go with Alice to buy some
clothes. Hello, Mr.
Smith. I'm afraid Dr.
Brown won't be able to see you today.
He's still waiting for a flight out of New York.
He said he would meet you tomorrow afternoon.
Is it okay?
Sounds good. Thank you for calling.
David, have you saved enough for the car?
I have $20,000 now, and the car costs $25,000.
My parents said they would like to help, but I don't want to use their money.
Dr. I need to take a few days off because my father is coming over to visit, and I
need to show him around the city.
Okay, Jane, but be sure to come back to work next week.
Amy, my head is spinning.
It must be a touch of the You'd better lie back still for a while.
Take it easy for the rest of the day, and stay in the shade.
It's too hot today.
第一节到此结束。
第二节，听下面五段对话或独白，
每段对话。
或独白后，有几个小题。
从题中所给的
三个选项中，选出最佳选项。
听每段对话或独白前，你将有时间。
阅读各个小题。
每小题五秒钟。
听完后，各小题将给出五秒钟的作答时间。
每段对话或独白读两遍。
听下面一段对话，回答
第六和第七两个小题。
现在你有十秒钟的时间
阅读这两个小题。
questions. Mom, this is going to forever.
Animal World will be on in 20 minutes.
It's my favorite program.
You know I can't miss it.
I know, honey, but we have to wait in line to pay for these things we need.
You promised we'd be home in time.
Be a little patient, We'll get out of here soon.
Mom, this is going to forever.
Animal World will be on in 20 minutes.
It's my favorite program.
You know I can't miss it.
I know, honey, but we have to wait in line to pay for these things we need.
You promised we'd be home in time.
Be a little patient, Jack.
We'll get out of here soon.
听下面一段对话，回答
第八至第十三个小题。
现在你有十五秒钟的时间。
阅读这三个小题。
Hi, Samantha. Do you have a minute?
Hi, Richard. Come in, please.
I've been trying to get hold of you all afternoon.
I was at the weekly manager's meeting.
How are things?
Oh, splendid. I have some news.
Good news? Wonderful news.
To me, anyway.
I've been offered a job for three years as an assistant to Professor Hayes from
Birmingham University.
I'll join him in Mexico City.
What do you think about that?
Wonderful, Richard. Just what you've always wanted, isn't it?
Does it mean that you'll leave soon?
Next week. But before I go, I'd like to invite you out for dinner.
Just to thank you for all the help you gave me during my three -month research work
here. Would tomorrow evening be a good time for you?
We can go to the Shanghai restaurant in Chinatown.
Fine with me.
Hi, Samantha. Do you have a minute?
Hi, Richard. Come in, please.
I've been trying to get hold of you all afternoon.
I was at the weekly manager's meeting.
How are things?
splendid. I have some news.
Good news? Wonderful news.
To me, anyway.
I've been offered a job for three years as an assistant to Professor Hayes from
Birmingham University.
I'll join him in Mexico City.
What do you think about that?
Wonderful, Richard. Just what you've always wanted, isn't it?
Does it mean that you'll leave soon?
Next week. But before I go, I'd like to invite you out for dinner.
Just to thank you for all the help you gave me during my three -month research work
here. Would tomorrow evening be a good time for you?
We can go to the Shanghai restaurant in Chinatown.
Fine with me.
听下面一段对话，回答
第十一至第十三三个小题。
现在你有十五秒钟的时间
阅读。
出这三个小题。
that book you just picked up, Mary?
The one Professor Lee uses in his course.
Oh, I see.
You'd better have it if you want to pass that course.
But it costs thirty dollars.
I simply can't afford it.
Did you check the used book section here?
Maybe they have it.
No, they don't.
I asked. Why don't you get it from the library?
I've been trying for months, and it's always out.
There are over fifty students in the course, and every single one wants the Listen,
you know my roommate Henry, don't you?
He took the same course last year, and I remember he owns a copy.
I can borrow it from him for you.
Oh, that'll be great.
Thank you, Jim.
What's that book you just picked up, Mary?
The one Professor Lee uses in his course.
Oh, I see.
You'd better have it if you want to pass that course.
But it costs thirty dollars.
I simply can't afford it.
Did you check the used book section here?
Maybe they have it.
No, they don't.
I asked. Why don't you get it from the library?
I've been trying for months, and it's always out.
There are over fifty students in the course, and every single one wants the Listen,
you know my roommate Henry, don't you?
He took the same course last year, and I remember he owns a copy.
I can borrow it from him for you.
Oh, that'll be great.
Thank you, Jim.
听下面一段对话，回答
第十四至第十六三个小题。
现在你有十五秒钟的时间
阅读这三个小题。
Hello? Hello, Stella.
This is Peter.
Hi, Peter. Fancy hearing your voice.
How are you?
Couldn't be better.
I'm planning a trip to Memphis with my family this summer.
Great! I'd love to host you here.
When are you coming?
We'll leave Boston on June 20th, stay in St.
Missouri for a week, and then fly to your city.
We'd probably stay for five days with you and come back, for it's a two -week
vacation. Is there anything special you'd like to do here?
We'd love to explore Beale Street, the official home of the blues, where we'd listen
to live music.
We'd also like to visit Graceland, the popular museum in memory of Elvis Presley.
But above all, we want to spend some time with you and your family.
Of course. It's been ages since we met last time.
Let's have a dinner party in my garden.
Lovely. Oh, could you find for us a hotel near where you live?
It doesn't have to be big, but I can't stand noise at bedtime.
Sure. Thank you.
See you soon.
Hello? Hello, Stella.
This is Peter.
Hi, Peter. Fancy hearing your voice.
How are you?
Couldn't be better.
I'm planning a trip to Memphis with my family this summer.
Great! I'd love to host you here.
When are you coming?
We'll leave Boston on June 20, stay in St.
Missouri for a week, and then fly to your city.
We'd probably stay for five days with you and come back, for it's a two -week
vacation. Is there anything special you'd like to do here?
We'd love to explore Beale Street, the official home of the blues, where we'd listen
to live music.
We'd also like to visit Graceland, the popular museum in memory of Elvis Presley.
But above all, we want to spend some time with you and your family.
Of course. It's been ages since we met last time.
Let's have a dinner party in my garden.
Lovely. Oh, could you find for us a hotel near where you live?
It doesn't have to be big, but I can't stand noise at bedtime.
Sure. Thank you.
See you soon.
Thank Hello, everyone.
听下面一段独白。
回答第十七至第二十四个小题。
现在你有二十秒钟的时间
阅读这四个小题。
My name is John.
I'm the teaching assistant for this lab session.
Let me explain a little about it.
As you may know already, it's a required meeting once a week.
I expect you to do all the experiments and keep the results in your lab notebook.
I'll collect the notebooks every two weeks.
You'll be graded on lab notebooks and quizzes.
But the most important information I want to give you now is about safety.
First of all, you must wear shoes that cover your feet in the lab.
Tennis shoes are okay.
Also, don't wear loose clothes, long scarves, big necklaces, or loose belts.
They get caught in something or fall into liquid.
Another thing to do for safety is cleaning up.
Be sure to put the waste in the correct containers.
We can't mix liquid with paper.
This is extremely important.
I don't want any fires in this room.
You are responsible for washing out your own lab equipment and putting it away.
If you don't do this, I will take away points from your grade.
Nobody's going to clean up after you.
Okay. Any questions?
Hello, everyone. My name is John.
I'm the teaching assistant for this lab session.
Let me explain a little about it.
As you may know already, it's a required meeting once a week.
I expect you to do all the experiments and keep the results in your lab notebook.
I'll collect the notebooks every two weeks.
You'll be graded on lab notebooks and quizzes.
But the most important information I want to give you now is about safety.
First of all, you must wear shoes that cover your feet in the lab.
You must If you don't do this, I will take away points from your grade.
Nobody's going to clean up after you.
Okay. Any questions?
第二节到此结束。
现在，你有两分钟的时间
将。试卷上的答案，转涂到答题卡上。
Thank you. Thank you.
听力部分到此结束。